# Mario Altagracia Jimenez

1908 Willow Creek Dr Austin, TX 512-994-1887 Jimernez.io@gmail.com Github.com/Toughee

## Web Developer

4 year of freelance programming experience for government and media industry. Dedicated web developer focused on front end software development. Experienced in building web applications emphasizing on responsive design for different browsers and devices. Able to work and adjust myself in any team environment. Capable of learning any tool or software needed complete the work assigned.

## **Work Experience**

## **Holiday Inn Express,** Austin, TX

Help Desk Agent

Nov 2017 - Present

Tech support for hotel guests and clients. Helped 70% of hotel guest's with their connectivity issues in a 7 month period. Fixed all guest's networking issues promptly

- Helped resolve troubleshooting problems for laptop computers and mobile devices
- Fixed connectivity and I.P. issues for Apple products
- Environment: macOS, iOS

### Code for America, Durham, NC

Nov 2016 - June 2017

Web Developer

Collaborative volunteer position for the City of Durham and the Government of North Carolina. Worked alongside a group of different web developers to help transfer and update old data from an outdated application. Managed to launch application for public use before deadline.

- Debugged, updated and fixed U/I issues
- Regularly collaborated with a small team to resolve project issues
- Environment: Ruby on rails, Adobe creative suite, Github, Docker

### Sx3 Consulting Firm, San Juan, PR

November 2013 – May 2014

Founder and UI Developer

Independent startup company developed entirely by myself focused on media and entertainment industry. Organized client work alongside a national commutations platform. Finished weekly client work collaborating with a team of 5 employees. Achieved highest viewer ratings in company's website from client work.

- Designed user interface for company's website
- Created branding strategies for different clients
- Environment: Adobe Creative Suite, Final Cut Pro

## Terra (Independant game), San Juan, P.R.

Software engineer/ game designer

March 2011 - July 2011

Independent action adventure game developed using the Unity game engine. Finished developing a playable demo for the first level of the game. Development was canceled due to lack of funding and direction.

- Developed a playable 3<sup>rd</sup> person open world game demo using C#
- Programmed audio tracks and stage environment music
- Environment: C#, Microsoft Visual Studio Basic, Unity

# Mario Altagracia Jimenez

1908 Willow Creek Dr Austin, TX 512-994-1887 Jimernez.io@gmail.com Github.com/Toughee

### **Skills**

Web languages: HTML, CSS3, Python, HTML5, JavaScript

Frameworks / Libraries: Bootstrap, Django, React

Version Control: Git

**Servers and Databases:** PostgresSQL, Node.js, npm, mySQL, Docker **Operating Systems:** Windows 8, Windows 10, macOS, Linux/Unix

**Desktop Publishing Software:** Adobe Creative Suite, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

**Collaboration tools:** Slack, Github **Fluent in:** English, Spanish, French

**Interpersonal Skills:** Project management, problem solving, data analysis, wireframing

## Open Source

### Adopt a drain Durham

Civic volunteer application

https://adoptadrain.codefordurham.com/

### **GDPdig**

Financial data application. Shows financial data for different states inside North America <a href="https://github.com/Touqhee/GDPdia">https://github.com/Touqhee/GDPdia</a>

### uPetitBio

Data visualizer for your personal data <a href="https://github.com/Toughee/uPetitBio">https://github.com/Toughee/uPetitBio</a>

## **Education**

**Sacred Heart University** B.A in **Advertising** 

Aug 2011 – May 2016